<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justin Davis</title>
    <description>UX guy. Javascript hacker. Founder of Madera Labs and Drawer.</description>
    <link>http://justindavis.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://justindavis.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Open Source Contribution: Node Amazon Products API</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been developing for almost 20 years now, about half of that professionally. While I’ve used countless open source libraries and packages in that time, I’ve never contributed one of my own. Whether it was that I never felt up to the task or the opportunity never presented itself, it doesn’t matter - that streak is now broken. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple days ago, I released &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/amz-products&quot;&gt;amz-products&lt;/a&gt;, an npm module that allows an easy interface to the Amazon Product Advertising API. As I’m using the API on a project with my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joshtronic.com&quot;&gt;Josh&lt;/a&gt;, it just made sense to package up what I’d created there and release it as open source. Thanks Josh, for the pushing to get this out into the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why this particular package? Well, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fetchlogic/amz-products/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;as the readme on the project states&lt;/a&gt;, I couldn’t find a good package on npm that seemed to work well for this API. Sure, there are a number of Amazon Product API packages out there, but each had weirdnesses about it. Either it had arcane authentication or other interfaces, or it only covered one or two endpoints of the API. Not satisfied with difficult-to-use or incomplete packages, I put this together to provide an easy and comprehensive solution to interacting with the Amazon Products API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The package itself is pretty straightforward. It’s a fairly thin wrapper around the API, but helps solve issues like authentication and response formats, which are pretty horrible in the native Amazon API. I’m hoping that folks find it easy to use and a good solution for getting data from the API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your project needs to consume product data from Amazon, I’d suggest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/amz-products&quot;&gt;giving my module a look&lt;/a&gt;. If you have suggestions for making it better, leave them in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fetchlogic/amz-products/issues&quot;&gt;project issues&lt;/a&gt;, send me a pull request, or just leave them in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/12/07/my-first-open-source-contribution-node-amazon-products-api/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/12/07/my-first-open-source-contribution-node-amazon-products-api/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buy Me Lunch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I get asked on a regular basis for advice, and I geniunely enjoy giving it. I love chatting with people to help them work through problems, especially as it relates to the design of technology products, be they websites, apps or other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, over the years, my time has gotten more and more at a premium, and I’ve been able to do less and less consulting or other types of engagements where I can sit down and chat through problems with folks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to change that. I eat lunch every day, and it makes sense to devote that time to helping other folks with their design and development problems. So, I’m kicking something off for the month of Decemeber: buy me lunch, and I’ll sit with you and chat through whatever you’re trying to solve. Easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you’re unfamiliar, my expertise is primarily in the UX arena, having nearly a decade of experience doing solely that. I’ve also created and launched countless sites and apps on my own, and can handle the development side of things pretty well also (particularly in the Javascript/Node area). Put simply, if you’re bringing some kind of tech product to market, I can probably help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-like-lunch-where-do-i-sign-up&quot;&gt;I Like Lunch. Where Do I Sign Up?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, interested in doing lunch? Let’s do this. I’ve chosen 5 restaurants nearby where I typically am during the day (in Ybor City, Tampa) - all you have to do is choose a spot and pick a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what you need to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://letsdolunch.youcanbook.me&quot;&gt;Find a time and book me here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet me there and buy lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you out at lunch soon! I can’t wait to help you out with whatever you’re struggling through!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/12/01/buy-me-lunch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/12/01/buy-me-lunch/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Command Line Arguments in a Node Script</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve found myself writing a lot of Node.JS scripts that are run from the command line. In fact, just last week, we looked at how to set up Node.JS modules to run from the command line. Continuing that line of exploration, let’s look at how to pass arguments to these scripts when running them from the command line. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve interacted with the command line much, you’ve undoubtedly seen arguments passed to CLI scripts. Take, for example, a git commit: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &quot;Your Message Here&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this command, you see that we pass an argument using the &lt;code&gt;-m&lt;/code&gt; flag, followed by the contents of our argument, our commit message. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at a couple ways to do this with Node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-1-simple-arguments&quot;&gt;Option 1: Simple Arguments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s pretend we have a simple Node script that gets the weather from some api. We’ll say that you call this on the command line using the &lt;code&gt;weather&lt;/code&gt; keyword. It’d be nice for our script to work in either Fahrenheit or Celsuis, to support our international users. So, how would we pass an option to our script to let it know which units to use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the design of the interface on the command line. We’ve decided that we should pass a simple flag to indicate which unit to use, which would looks like this: &lt;code&gt;weather -f&lt;/code&gt;. This would return weather in Fahrenheit units. Using &lt;code&gt;weather -c&lt;/code&gt; might return in Celsius. (A quick note: it’s likely you’d have this script default to one or the other, thus only passing the flag as an override, but you get the idea)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so how does our Node script know what do with this information? Here’s a solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var units = process.argv[2];
if(units == &#39;-f&#39;){
    this.setUnits(&#39;Fahrenheit&#39;);
} else {
    this.setUnits(&#39;Celsius&#39;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy enough. We’re using the &lt;code&gt;process.argv&lt;/code&gt; directive to grab arguments from the CLI, and parse those out in the script. In this example, we’re enforcing order: the second item in the &lt;code&gt;process.argv&lt;/code&gt; array is the first argument (the first item is the name of script itself). This is good for simple arguments, especially where you may just have a single arugment or flag passed to the script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-2-flag-and-argument-pairs&quot;&gt;Option 2: Flag and Argument Pairs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous example, we have a simple flag that tells our script what unit to use for temperature, but what if we wanted to pass more information? For example, what if we wanted to pass the city &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; unit into our weather script?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this, we can get a little more sophisticated, using flag and argument pairs, not unlike our git example at the start of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, this is how we’d like to pass things to the script: &lt;code&gt;weather -f -c Tampa,FL&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I’ve included both flags: temp and city. I might also just want to pass city: &lt;code&gt;weather -c Tampa,FL&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, using the declarative approach to argument order won’t really work, since the unit flag is optional. How, then, can we retrieve the city argument if it exists?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var city;
if(process.argv.indexOf(&quot;-c&quot;) != -1){ //does our flag exist?
    city = process.argv[process.argv.indexOf(&quot;-c&quot;) + 1]; //grab the next item
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like that, we’ve got the city, regardless of where it appears in the order of arguments. Our snippet here is simply checking to see if the flag has been passed, and if so, getting the element in the array that directly follows it. Piece of cake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using arguments and flags like this on the command line is infinitely useful, and if you’re using Node on the CLI, you’ll find these tricks to be really helpful ways of making your scripts more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have some great command line tricks for Node? Leave them in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/11/24/using-command-line-arguments-in-a-node-script/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/11/24/using-command-line-arguments-in-a-node-script/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Just Ship.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of people with ideas in the world, but to find people who actually have decent ideas &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; have the guts and discipline to create them, well, that’s exceedingly rare. People tell me about their ideas a lot. Because I work in the tech and product design world, I get pitched on a lot of stuff. But I’ve come to a disappointing conclusion: most people are full of shit. They can’t execute, and it’s too damn bad. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about your ideas is pointless. Sure, it’s good to get feedback and help hone your concept, but until you actually build &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; ship the thing, you’re just blowing smoke. Another idea guy with nothing but talk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it, you think it’s hard to do this stuff, that it takes too much time, that you don’t have the talent. These are all excuses, nothing but excuses. Each objection you have to shipping your idea out the door into the world is nothing but a combination of fear and laziness. Just ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the beautiful thing about shipping: the more you ship, the better you get at it, and the less fear you have. Have an idea for a website? Give yourself a week to build it, then ship it. I don’t care if it’s the ugliest thing in the world, ship it. Have an idea for a new business? Write the business plan, summary, pitch deck, whatever you have to do, and go present it to someone. Like, within the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people say that you just need to get started. “Just take the first step”, they’ll say. To be honest, I used to say the same thing. But I’ve realized it’s all bullshit. Starting is important, but shipping is 10x more important. You can start all you want, but if you never get it into the world, it’s worthless. &lt;em&gt;Worthless&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, listen. If you’ve ever said, “I want to build a…” or “It’d be cool if we could create…” or “I want to start…”, then just do it. But don’t just go through the motions. Get it out the door, FAST, and start making it into something awesome. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no points for talking or building, only shipping. Just ship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/11/24/just-ship/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/11/24/just-ship/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Running Node Modules from the Command Line</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to run node.js modules from the command line is a really useful thing, especially if you’re building an app that runs on a server, and might occasionally need to have pieces of it invoked manually. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s pretend you had an app that creates some kind of report, say, analytics for your site. You might have created a node module called &lt;code&gt;report.js&lt;/code&gt; that runs the reports, given a type of report you pass into one of the methods. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume that script looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
var reporter = {};
reporter.createReport = function(reportType){
    //your logic to create a report
}

module.exports = reporter;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This very simple module exports a method called &lt;code&gt;createReport&lt;/code&gt;, which can be included in your application and called, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var reporter = require(&quot;./reporter&quot;);
reporter.createReport(&quot;site analytics&quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, what if you want to also be able to manually kick this off from the command line, in case someone asks you to run a report on the fly? Well, we can easily refactor our module to permit us to do just that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s our refactored module:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/usr/bin/env node

(function(){
    var reporter = {};
    exports.createReport = reporter.createReport = function(reportType){
        //your logic to create a report
    });

    if (!module.parent) {
        reporter.createReport(process.argv[2]);
    }
})();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s break down what we’ve done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First, we’ve slightly modified how things are constructed on the object, choosing to assign our method to both the &lt;code&gt;exports&lt;/code&gt; variable and to make it a method on &lt;code&gt;reporter&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then, we’ve added logic that checks to see if this module has been required in by another script, and if not, runs our method with arguments from the command line as the arguments for the method. The &lt;code&gt;module.parent&lt;/code&gt; call is a Node call that returns &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; if this module has been required by another file. By checking to see if the value is &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;, we’re telling our script that this wasn’t required by another file, and must have been executed as a stand alone file (such as from the command line).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, we wrap all of this in a self-invoking anonymous function, so our module logic runs immediately once the file is called.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it! Now, you can call this file as we did above where it was required into another file, or you can call it from the command line like this: &lt;code&gt;./reporter &quot;site analytics&quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that if you don’t include the shebang in the file, you’ll need to prepend your CLI call with &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BOOM! Now your node modules can be included and invoked from another file, or simply run ala carte from the command line. I’ve found a lot of uses for this, and hope you do as well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/11/16/running-node-modules-from-the-command-line/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/11/16/running-node-modules-from-the-command-line/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Focusing on the Right Things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I see this happen all the time. Someone launches their entrepreneural journey, thrusting themselves out into the world to hang a shingle and try to create something of their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, shit gets messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They start worrying about letterheads, buying t-shirts and other swag, getting nicer chairs for the office and a myriad of other time-wasting tasks. More often than not, what’s left of the startup is a box of t-shirts in the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be real clear on one thing: anything that doesn’t &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; lead to customers trasacting with you is a waste of time in those early days. In those early days, cash is at a premium, and your entire goal is to get a product into the market and find out if people want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. You’re not building a brand here. You’re not changing the world, yet. You’re trying to get the first 10 people to say that what you’re doing is valuable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such an amateur mistake, and it’s easy to spot people who’ve never built anything before based on these activities. Do yourself a favor, stop doing anything that isn’t directly about building and delivering product to your customers. That’s it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you need a reminder, here’s what you should be doing in the early days of your startup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shipping product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talking to customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. Note that there’s nothing in there about window treatments, coffee machines and stickers. Starting a company is ridiculously hard work, you don’t have the luxury to waste resources at this point - start focusing relentlessly on those above bullet points, and cut everything else out.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/11/10/focusing-on-the-right-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/11/10/focusing-on-the-right-things/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Asus PB278 Dual Monitor Setup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded my monitor situation at the house, moving from a 37″ VISIO TV (I know, right?) to a set of dual 27″ monitors. I was looking for something with higher resolution, and also wanted the dual setup to give me more space for working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought was to jump on a pair of Apple Thunderbolt displays, but at $1K a pop, it was a little outside of the budget. Instead, I looked around and landed on a pair of ASUS PB278Q Monitors. Let me tell you, they’re pretty incredible, and at over half the price of a Thunderbolt display, they’re a perfect option if you’re not up for dropping all that coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been running this setup for a day now, here’s how things look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropbox.com/s/oemuqdt7e88z12e/IMG_0044.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Asus PB278 Dual Monitor Setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monitors have super crisp graphics, and are a great substitute for the Retina display on the Macbook Pro that I’m running things from. I currently have one running on HDMI straight from the computer, and the other on DisplayPort. I’ll probably eventually go with both on DisplayPort, just to make things consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for specs, here’s how things look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen size: 27′&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aspect Ratio: 16:9&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Max resolution: 2560×1400&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WQHD support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accepts VGA, Dual-Link DVI, HDMI 1.4, DisplayPort 1.2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tilt, vertical movement and base rotation for adjusting the viewing angle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I’m damn happy with them. My only real gripe is that you can’t daisy chain them with DisplayPort, which means you’ll need a splitter or two ports to run them. Not a huge deal either way. BTW, if you buy one, don’t forget your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00HNF0KF0/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00HNF0KF0&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=daondr-20&amp;amp;linkId=SPSYI55ES45PP6QW&quot;&gt;Mini DisplayPort to DisplayPort adapter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00C7RJQPY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00C7RJQPY&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=daondr-20&amp;amp;linkId=42T3EEL5UVL4KSPJ&quot;&gt;cable&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple other shots of the monitors, to give you a full feel for them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropbox.com/s/nm9s70arvb7ruvv/IMG_0045.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Asus PB278 Monitor&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropbox.com/s/njifwdnbirtbyh1/IMG_0046.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Asus PB278 Monitor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d highly recommend you take a look at them if you’re looking to upgrade your setup. One would be awesome, two is just incredible. At about $450/monitor they’re less than half the price of the Thunderbolt Displays, but definitely don’t leave you wanting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grab them on Amazon here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009C3M7H0/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B009C3M7H0&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=daondr-20&amp;amp;linkId=YNZWQQUM35CCSBOV&quot;&gt;ASUS PB278Q 27-Inch WQHD LED-lit Professional Graphics Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/11/01/review-asus-pb278q-lcd-monitor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/11/01/review-asus-pb278q-lcd-monitor/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Determine if a number is in the Fibonacci series using JavaScript</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a conversation with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshtronic.com&quot;&gt;buddy of mine&lt;/a&gt; who is a kick ass dev. We had been chatting about working on little academic problems, as a way to increase your understanding of code and algorithms. Since we usually build for the web, where things are much more practical, spending some time on contrived problems like this is challenging and helps you think more deeply about solving problems using code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we started tinkering with a question he was asked in an interview recently. How would you find out if a number is in the Fibonacci series? You can’t simply match against the entire series, as theoretically, the series is infinite, and you’d run out of memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked up a solution using Javascript that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;isFib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;val&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;yes!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;curr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;nope&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;isFib&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;89&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//for example, check if 89 is in the series&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solution essentially crawls through the series, looking for a match against the value given when calling the function. It should be fairly memory conservative, as we’re only storing the current and previous values of the walk. It’s also quite fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would you improve this? Can this be made more efficient? Give your suggestions in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more awesome little challenges like this, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackerrank.com&quot;&gt;HackerRank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/10/30/determine-if-a-number-is-in-the-fibonacci-series-using-javascript/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/10/30/determine-if-a-number-is-in-the-fibonacci-series-using-javascript/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Sass with Titanium Alloy Style Sheets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, using CSS frameworks and preprocessors, like LESS and Sass, is an important part of efficient frontend development workflow. These new approaches allow us to use things like variables, mixins, inheritance and imports to make our CSS more flexible, more DRY, and more modular. In short, it makes writing CSS less of a pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you’re a Titanium developer? How can you harness the power of these CSS tools when styling your app using Alloy TSS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STSS to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;STSS is a NPM package that brings the power of Sass into Titanium, allowing you to use all those sexy Sass features in your Titanium apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started is easy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;g&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed the package globally on my machine, but you can it locally in your project if you want. If you install globally like I did, add an Alloy pre-compile hook so that Titanium will compile the STSS files into TSS files before building the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get that pre-compile hook set up, go to your project directory and do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stss&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;jmk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve done that, you’re in business! Start naming your Alloy style sheets with a `.stss’ extension, and enjoy the wonderful power of Sass in your Titanium apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/stss&quot;&gt;check out the official NPM package here&lt;/a&gt;. To learn about Sass and all the ways it’ll change your life, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sass-lang.org/&quot;&gt;check out their site.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/10/14/using-sass-with-titanium-alloy-style-sheets/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/10/14/using-sass-with-titanium-alloy-style-sheets/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Books Every Parent-To-Be MUST READ</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My wife and I just had our first baby almost 4 weeks ago (Haley Jane, if you’re curious). Obviously, going into this whole thing, we had all kinds of questions, and felt like we needed to get some good guidance on how to make sure we don’t screw up this little human that we’re bringing into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the 9 month journey toward parenthood, we read three books that have made these first 4 weeks so much easier than it could have otherwise been. Just last night, our daughter slept through the night for the first time…at 4 weeks!
So, without further ado, the three books that we read, that I think every parent-to-be should read. The piece of mind and confidence that these books give you is priceless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;babywise&quot;&gt;Babywise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Babywise, by Gary Ezzo and Robert Bucknam, is all about getting your infant to sleep through the night, by way of getting them on a predictable feeding and napping schedule throughout the day. The authors discuss the different approaches to feeding: Child-Led feeding, Clock Feeding, and their approach, Parent-Directed Feeding, which is a blend of paying attention to hunger cues, to the clock, and parental assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They cover in depth the science behind sleep and how feeding affects sleeping, and offer detailed schedules for feeding and sleeping from 2 weeks through a year. Their approach uses “merges” to merge separate feedings at night until you’ve merged all the middle-of-the-night feedings out, and are sleeping through the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book goes pretty deep into some of the science, and certainly offers a deep explanation about the why behind their schedule-based approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.today/o/zhlgU/http://www.amazon.com/On-Becoming-Baby-Wise-Nighttime/dp/1932740139/ref=as_sl_pc_ss_til?tag=daondr-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w01&amp;amp;linkId=XKGNHCL2GGTQCO5Q&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1932740139&quot;&gt;Buy Babywise on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moms-on-call&quot;&gt;Moms on Call&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moms On Call is another book that’s based around the notion of scheduling, but is far more of a handbook than an exhaustive resource in the science of feeding and sleeping. Thus, this book makes a perfect companion to Babywise, as the two compliment each other quite nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moms On Call is brief, with short little “chapters” covering everything from sleep, to feeding, to dealing with sick kids, to skin care. It’s quite exhaustive, but brief on each of the topics. This format is awesome. It’s the perfect reference book for those early weeks, since you can easily turn to a section and quickly get up to speed on the basics for almost anything that would happen with your baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book also features detailed schedules, and we found ourselves following their schedules more than Babywise, simply due to the detail they go into (while the rest of the book is brief, the schedule component is quite detailed).
The authors also have a website (and service, based in Atlanta) where they feature videos about how to swaddle, diaper changing, and other important items. A fantastic resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.today/o/zhlgU/http://www.amazon.com/Moms-Call-Basic-Baby-Care-ebook/dp/B00AN2JPNI/ref=as_sl_pc_ss_til?tag=daondr-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w01&amp;amp;linkId=45G7NAJXOS6GSAWZ&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00AN2JPNI&quot;&gt;Buy Moms on Call on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-happiest-baby-on-the-block&quot;&gt;The Happiest Baby on the Block&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey Karp’s book is one of the books that I get recommended to me most often. His book is about soothing crying babies (particularly those with Colic), and goes into detail about crying and how to settle little ones down. His focus, like the other two, is on helping them calm down so they can sleep better as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most famous in Karp’s book is the 5 S’s, which is his framework for how to calm a crying baby: Swaddle, Side/Stomach Position, Shhhhhhing sounds, Swinging and Sucking. These 5 techniques are based in recreating the atmosphere of the uterus, which leads into one of central theses of the book: that babies are actually missing a fourth trimester, which is, in his view, the true cause of colic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for the 5 S’s alone, this book is a must read. These little tricks have saved us (and our daughter) from hours of misery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.today/o/zhlgU/http://www.amazon.com/Happiest-Baby-Block-Harvey-Karp/dp/0553381466/ref=as_sl_pc_ss_til?tag=daondr-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w01&amp;amp;linkId=WREPFQW5PRRBSG3T&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0553381466&quot;&gt;Buy Happiest Baby on the Block on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming a new parent is a shock to the system, to say the least. It’s a huge period of adjustment for you and your little one, and any help you can get from folks who’ve done it before and know what they’re talking about is worth seeking out. Of all the resources and tips we’ve gotten over the past 10 months, these books have been elevated in our household to absolutely critical status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a new parent, about to be, or just want to figure out how to calm your baby and get them to sleep through the night, don’t miss these books!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://justindavis.co/2014/09/20/three-books-every-parent-to-be-must-read/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://justindavis.co/2014/09/20/three-books-every-parent-to-be-must-read/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
